Guide to the Disabled American Veterans Dept. of Montana records -
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Disabled American Veterans Department of Montana records
1945 - 1984
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
10:9-1
This collection consists of records of the Disable Veterans of America, Department of Montana, including correspondence, financial records, membership records, and organizational records. Collection also includes records of the DAV Auxillary that include financial records, membership records, organizational records, and scrapbooks.
by subgroup and series
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Veterans--Montana
Montana
Military
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Disabled American Veterans, Dept.of Montana, 1945-1984
  - General Correspondence
    - Correspondence between organization leadership and members (some files include membership lists and financial records), 1945-1980 (Box-folder 1 / 1-11)
    - Department of Montana Adjutant correspondence files, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 2 / 1-7)
    - Department of Montana Commander correspondence files, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 2 / 8-9)
    - National Executive Committee files, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 3 / 1-6)
    - National Finance Committee files, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 3 / 7-10)
  - Organizational Records
    - Constitution, By-laws, scattered minutes, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 3 / 11-12)
  - Financial Records
    - Scattered financial records, including journal (1952-1974); ledger sheets (1950-1959) recording dues and expenses; monthly reports to national organization (1960-1975); bills (1975), 1950-1975 (Box-folder 4 / All)
  - Subject Files
    - Greeting Cards (fund raising); Perpetual Rehabilitation Fund; DAV van, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 5 / 1-8)
  - Miscellany
    - National DAV convention and legislative materials, 1950s-1980s (Box-folder 6 / All)
- Office of Adjutant, Havre, 1980s
  - Financial Records
    - Treasurer reports and receipts (relating mostly to membership and greeting cards fundraisers), 1980s (Box-folder 7-8 / All)
- DAV Auxiliary, 1950s-1980s
  - Financial Records
    - Records include treasurer reports, receipts, banking records (includes scattered correspondence), 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 9-11 / All)
  - Miscellany
    - Scrapbooks (including photographs, clippings, memorabelia, correspondence, certificates), 1950s-1980s (Box-folder 12 / All)